<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vlad's blog</title><link>https://rk4n.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Vlad's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rk4n.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stand With Ukraine</title><link>https://rk4n.github.io/stand-with-ukraine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rk4n.github.io/stand-with-ukraine/</guid><description>On Feb 24, 2022, Russia launched a full-scale war against Ukraine, causing immense suffering for the Ukrainian people. In response, many organizations and individuals have come forward to show their support and solidarity with Ukraine.
One way to help is through donations to various foundations and charitable organizations that are working to support Ukraine.
Leleka Foundation The Come Back Alive Fund Nova Ukraine Razom Charity foundation of Serhiy Prytula Ukraine Armed Forces You can also check #StandWithUkraine website for more information and ways to help.</description></item><item><title>🐘 Vacuum your Elephants: improving PostgreSQL performance with autovacuum</title><link>https://rk4n.github.io/2020/05/01/vacuum-your-elephants-improving-postgresql-performance-with-autovacuum/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rk4n.github.io/2020/05/01/vacuum-your-elephants-improving-postgresql-performance-with-autovacuum/</guid><description>Written by: Vlad Nikityuk and Valentin Lavrinenko.
Originally posted in the People.ai Engineering Blog
People.ai helps companies increase sales and marketing effectiveness by providing business data insights and helping with data input automation. At People.ai, we use various relational and NoSQL databases to process and store business data. In this article, we will focus on the PostgreSQL database, its internals, and some of the performance tweaks.
This story is about how we faced some critical performance issues with one of our database replicas and how we resolved all that burden with the correct Postgres autovacuum config.</description></item><item><title>🚀 QEMU Live Migrations: Post-Copy and Auto-Converge features</title><link>https://rk4n.github.io/2016/08/10/qemu-live-migrations-post-copy-and-auto-converge-features/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 15:59:04 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://rk4n.github.io/2016/08/10/qemu-live-migrations-post-copy-and-auto-converge-features/</guid><description>Photo by Barth Bailey on Unsplash
Cloud lifecycle is a complex process that involves several procedures such as maintenance and upgrades. These operations mostly include migration of workloads. OpenStack provides several options to perform such moving:
Cold migration Live migrations Instance rebuilds From the list above only live migration allows moving an instance from one host to another with almost *zero downtime, which is done seamlessly for the instance itself.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://rk4n.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rk4n.github.io/about/</guid><description>My name is Vlad Nikityuk, and this is my blog where I write thoughts on technologies I work with daily.
Right now, I’m building a text-checking API in Grammarly.
Previously I worked on knowledge graph in People.ai and Enterprise OpenStack features in Mirantis.
My Linkedin and Github.</description></item></channel></rss>